{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A square room has a hook on the ceiling exactly at the centre P. If AB is one of the sides of the floor, where <\/font><font style='font-family:Calibri;'> <img Width='12' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADlSURBVChThY+9jkVAGIbP9VDTq7UuwD24CSLRuwUaUSn0JCoJlRChk6gl\/t6z37eZs3vWkX2S18w7M89MPM7zBEHj3xzHwaG54CX8xzAMPL6Efd8vodsJx3FgWRbPbwVx2HVdmKaJdV253wqE53nQdR3LsnAnPgqE7\/tQFAXTNHEX6xeBiKIIsiyjaRruv\/feBCLPc6iqirIsudP6tm0\/gvg5oqoqaJqGoii4i5s\/Cm3bwjAM1HXN\/Y4Hffq+hyRJsG0bWZYhTdO3JEmCruu+BXphnmeEYcibcRxfEgQBxnH8Og48AfvuD9RbUUzkAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  <\/font><font style='font-family:Arial;'>APB = 60\u00b0 and AB = 6 m, then what is the height (in m) of the room?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Enter your answer as a decimal value, rounded off to two decimal places.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"4.24","CORRECT_ANSWER":"4.24","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>In how many ways can 60060 be written as a product of two factors?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16 ways\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32 ways\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48 ways\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>96 ways\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the sum of all possible values of <i>x<\/i>, if  <img Width='193' Height= '44' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAMAAAAAsCAYAAAAzWrf+AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAA5aSURBVHhe7Z0HkBRFF4APlKQIAiJJsoSiFATJWTIoQSQqQYIiRQkUgiTJkjP8gCQtBRNKPLJkJEOpgKJIBkFBcpLY\/3193UffMLc7u7d3t+zNV9XFdu+wO9vTr9\/r16\/fhQmXR4rz58+LYUOHiokTJ4lBgwaJ0aPHiHv37ql3XXzFFYBHjPAlS0Tx4iXE7du3xf59+8Rjjz0m1qxdp9518ZWw+\/fvi19\/\/VUcPnxYXLlyRTW7wLFjx8Qff\/whzpw5o1riBmbwXbt2CZ6FNy5fvhzxnK7K17dv3RJhYWFi3Ljxsh6f\/PPPP+qVZ+jDgwcPqlrwEUbnT5s2Tc4kM2bMUM2Bh+\/5+eefxQcffCCaNWsmqlSpIvr06SPOnTunrnjAunXr5DV169aV11y\/fl29E79s3LhRZMiQQbzyyiuqJfBs27ZNlCpVSnTr1s2RAJhM\/+QTkfbpp8XZsw\/3YaA4evSoaNOmjWjUqFFUKVasmGjRooW6wjM7duwQJUqUEF27dvX598UHUSbQ448\/LiZMmKBqgeeHH36Qs9W7774rfvnlF7F8+XKRJEkSUbRoUXHnzh11lRBr166V182bN0\/s3btX5M6dW1SoUEG96zu\/\/fab+CRioPjL66+\/Ll588UVVCyxLly4VyZMnF0sizBpf2bNnt8iYMaPYsmWranHGjz\/+KObOnatq3lm\/fr18HiVLlowq5cqVE19++aW6wjtYFjVq1JCTXrCtV6IE4Mknn4xYWE1UtcCzZcsW0bx5c1WLpG\/fvrJzEQhNnjx5RMOGDVVNSEHhGh6EP8ycOVOkTJlS1XynZcuW4qWXXlK1wHH16lWROnVqqX19BZMsa9asIjx8qWpxDprm+eefVzXvrFq1KmLNUVzV\/IeBnylTJjFixAjVEhxECcATTzzxkABgb06ZMkUMHjxYfPfdd7YqjBmb98eNGycWL14svvrqKzmzOYHOYHAfOHBA1o8cOSLrs2fPlnU4e\/asbOvcubNq8Y05c+aIbNmyqZrvvPXWW7YCwG8cMGCA1C4nTpxQrQ9gTTV27Fjpqfn+++\/F\/Pnz5e+6dOmSfH\/69Oni2Wefla81hw4dkjMr\/YjGhJ9++kksWLBAfP3111JT3o8YSGXKlBaTJ\/9Pvo9ZuWHDBvnaCf369ZMmiVNWr14ttXRMcH\/cG\/fMJAdoGX4zbSb85vTp04tbEWuXYCFGAeAB5syZU7Rt21aaI6g91B8zFyAM2IYvv\/yyfLjY9gzUOnXqyAfvhHz58kWzr\/Vsz+dpeOjp0qWTtqc\/oO4DKQD87iZNmojChQtLYe\/du7d46qmn5LpFs3DhQjm4GfCff\/65NPWyZMkiunTpIv7++295Tf78+UWnTp3ka82pU6dEpUqVZB\/MmjVLtq1YsULWhw8fLu7evSvmffutrPMsuC+eW8+eveS1Tujfv79PAsAzeeGFF6T7FZPUumbDgYLW5p6YDAFTmvoXX3wh6xo0F+3h4eGqJeGJUQBQe2ZHMXNx8927d5f1ffv2yfqaNWtkHXLkyCFatWqlap756KOP5HeePn1atQg5oPhMFk4mqPtq1aqpmm\/wmYEUAGYx7tH0gmDbZs6cWfz333+ynj179mgCi6mHiam5du2aXHNNnTpVtTzgxo0bsh\/5XnjvvffEsGHD5GtAS27fvl0ONvp+8+bNUULlBLQWwuMUBj0mExNbkSJFpFOgY8eO8j41J0+elM\/y448\/lvV69erJfrcDM6hnz56qlvDYCgAqnYc8adIkWdcwO6EVgI7nGgRBg5bAQ+ANZgBmRa0yNahSPhO1bsLs+dprr6maZ3jAzM66MBiTJUsWrY2CaneCVQCYFBgIJphZ3Pf+\/fulhkAjYGtr0EK8zwwPmDrUmV3twKxImjSp1DRo1tjwzjvvRPvdaCaetdlG4d5j4sKFC3LAo42XLVsm792qvdB6tOO982Tno\/n4XcGCrQDQGfwYq7egfv36cjYG1gd0JrPBzZs35UKW\/+NtUbd161Z5nZ3dqjvR9IpgL6ZNm9ax2+3333+Xn60Ls+8zzzwTrY3C2sIJVgFgNmTGN1m0aJG87507d8o6piFaB3MBDwhmYpkyZaI8IHv27JHXexJCzCWu+fPPP1WLf+g1gi5o6IIFC0Zro\/iyB8RExwKezTgTzFnu2dpugkevcuXKqpbw2AoAmxf8kMmTJ8u6BjWoNQBgp6KueeB4buxUugkDAtfdZ599ploi0X5+Np34XvNzUO+0+euiZfH+3HPPqZrvWAWAwWzVAKxZuEftzcLWzZs3r5zpGHDMlsyiGkwGrmdxawcTUNOmTWV\/44LF9g8UQ4YMEaVLl1Y1\/2BdiIbSJh+sXLlSvPnmm7J\/Xn31VdX6MIyX9u3bq1rCE00A9OyNqmN2x+QxSZEihdzQANQ4tqTZCd6oWbOmePvtt1Ut8nvoDBaKwIPGZGGG0WiziEHjD7H1AjGATS8IG3PcD3a8pnXr1tG8G9jA30YsVmMCjckawM5ZgKmBhmFnmP7gc9k7CRS+eoHQvLiSTZgE2bzTXsHjx4\/LZ8ZkxXNCOMaMGSPfM0ED4tBg\/RcsyFAIbHEeaq1ateRqH5BobFlcnNiqDRo0kN4APZOxOEqVKpX84ag0CjNATJs6qFm+AxOKQU7BNKENt5mGxR2D4\/3335eCweJy5MiR6l3f+fTTT6UJ5Q88WB4296hnd34\/GoFFOf0yatQokSZNGumt0TAxYOvSJ5gFtWvXloPdNA1wMrzxxhuqFslff\/0l202Ngxbh+z\/88MOA7IjzOYUKFVI171SvXl0OaPoR+x8bn2eo+wMXNnU0FjCpMWFwz6whTe2Fx4j2TZs2qZaERwoALjzsb9yd5kyL\/YkHAtcZ\/m7Tf4s7FFXKoOdB8pAxDfiBbJ5YoaO0P5tZmYLPm7aLFy+qqyLBBMB2x8VIOEJsYJBiSvgD94EJhU\/bXLAzkOkP+gXPh9VOZ4ZjhkTb0S8MIvqFBakGs8lqRqBV6Rf85\/Qv7\/GaPqJd7yHEBu4bjeWUf\/\/9V\/YBz4LfO378+Gj3wYKd54hwMNiZIFgT8fvQguaYQfhy5cqlasFBlAnkK0i8nWuS2bZHjx6qlvhA4AhvMN2EwDoAc0aDELGgbteunWoJbfS6x5cwjNiCmUqsFe5inDZ2+C0AuCULFCgQTS1rM8dOAyQWtEeImVHD4p++sg52nA2YD6wr9AZjKMJ6BpMwkGsZT2DGs1+FKYm2Y6JmTWvuc2n8FgAWPNiDeH\/4YXgGUPXmLm5iBJNy6NChomrVqnKBT9\/gPkYr6kWjCcJBPxLqYff+ow4zMGsh665wXKL3qEwvG5HFtLGRaOK3AGiw39ngYQHn8gDsYfqF4mTxanqVQgl+e3wLNhrADE2Bb775RgqANQwj1gLg4hJIEBYW\/96KrwF1BCUiAJidJq4AuAQVmNa42wmU9FRw2TsFzxR7WDqOzSSMBSuuTre4JT4LO\/vM5FbwjuF+Zp\/JUyFqwCmEXxCKYkcYN4P\/3i1uic9ClEF8eL46dOggw0liWmO5JpBLUMECls3Vxo0beywEC3qDCAJCLzwF+rkC4BJUMFgJp2aH3VPxFnVMuAWhNuYBHiKFdRgGcUmYYK4ABAG4Cr0VAuhcnMHA5gwJUakcXSWUhVASwjA4ugvsFbAz7wpAAkNIOWqah+GplC9fXv0PF28Qt0U2EULSOYFGYSeYsHjOowD\/UncFIIFhm3706NEyXsVT4RikizPwJGHiWAt7DOamHK9dAUhAOHqKh4KH45IwhKQAcKKMk1yeDqXEBUSC2qVIiQnMHzMHEqHH+MA5Z60LMfWJObgwrglJAdBHOuMz1Bhh4ztZbDmFkHKd\/gRYoPEZ1hJThgWX2BOyJhDht2yCxAekSOGEG\/lVCbpyAl4dMmhw6kzDcUVSCGLv68JBe9cDFHeErABw2IScOlaI0iThqye7m0Gp8\/6wUPJmo3NclNNSeGuchv2S6tGadJdTVyQYcIk\/EpUAkP2aM8wckmDw4X0xIb4Em5yjixxsJyiL45SsJ8yzrSaYMMT+cwIMDWB34okEvVZ69eolZ3wT2hLLCbFgIdEIgM4uwak1YEeQuk7BwmFuDsDrRSk7khzvRADIXme6zzS0c2ifs7ykkrTa65znJRMG7ebBf8Cvz2ERE85Bk7OHwzOcuBs4cKDj\/EUu\/pEoBIDZm3w01hBaBid5ihjcOhseh7s1zMaYNTHBICXPDuhsb2TTYCcSEwqvEDY8aRE5HK\/hED2H5s0sEYAGIgyA9IssiBFI1hbmOsElsCQKAdB5TZlhTchRSTuLTKIFeW2m9SOMlnOldrM\/moPrSQOD0JBFmzp5kzCzqGtIncJ7xKIA73GE1Bs6W7Y1DaFL4EgUAkBGAAYSh89NWHTSrjMGcGiagxPEqmOPs5XOgW47iC8hYzN5k8hHSopIPgutwPfowQ6sD\/hczggDiXOdeoswsWLzB0JcPBOyAmCmH8eLw0DCxWhCWC1BU9j\/XEM2MwoH+81EV07QaT8we+wgWS7v8\/eyGNDWv7GFOYRQWY\/6kXQLL5NL3BCSAsBgItUjnhwNseEMQJ15mrQl1PWfT+JQP4mqGPxcQ+YzdmXtTi3Zgabg87Df7WCXl3sqW7ZstPSQGiI++f+mliKbHG3BlEkt1AhJAcATgx3OwnP37t2qNfIv0pCiAzcnblAdGqvBncmAQxD4l8L5U\/0XbGICgSNGHc8OLladXtIKG3N8pjU5MLBQJ6Mcqcr5DFyvFStW9Ovvh7k4J2Q1gMbqaWFGZ7a3tpOCkZ1ZzptizmCq4MHBBPGWSpBFsrlPENPGGesCvE54jDxBdum4\/tOsLpGE7BrAV4jLIYbcCgvhQO7OkvXAzqvkkjC4AqAg8pL0hSR\/JakSWapxk5Ltzo3FCVWE+D+eHY3XgkFH6wAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/> \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the ratio of the sum of the first <i>n<\/i> terms (where <i>n<\/i> is any natural number) of two arithmetic progressions is given by  <img Width='41' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACkAAAAdCAYAAAA3i0VNAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAV8SURBVFhH7Zd7UJVFGMYREUxuohiQqEyKqTWVWCJy0S6AFkIpKmKFXY5oOGrQ5CSaosc\/QiDzBvzjaDlBJYoNB7FwzEAEx1CQyyDIjIoiclEUGNCBp33fs5wb56BO\/KEz\/mZ2Zp9993zfs2f3233XDCa4d+8eEhMTERUVxeXs2bMyMnBUV1fj65gYfv6+ffvQ3d0tI\/qYNDknMBCOjo6IiIiA5\/TpGD58OAoLC2X0\/3Pr1i2MGzsWU6d68Dvo+StWrpRRfYya\/DU9DWZmZsg\/fZo1jXDC+Bfh6+vH+sGDB7h+\/TrXCwoKkJOTg67791k\/KmvXrIG9MNbW1sb60O+\/8Ttrai6z1sWoybpr13As+5hUagID\/DHtjTe5rsrKgoODA8LCwrBgwQJMmjQJPj4+6Ozs5LguSqUSpRcvSqWlpaUFN27ckArYHh8PCwsLMXhtWy8mp1uXCxfO8yhTUlJZx8VtZr1z5y7Wx7JVrIvPn2etS0BAAHJPnJCqL38cPYrJkyfz7\/fsTZat+jzUZJn4FywtLfH5FwrZAvj6eGPKy69IBaQkJ\/NLrly5Klu0hIaG4kw\/a\/mfU6eQlJQEPz8\/jB8\/AWVl5TKipV+Tx8Vae27oUEQsWyZbgK6uLlgPG4aNG7+TLcDS8CUYPdoVPT09rFNTU6FQKLi4ubkhKChIo0tKSrmPIR3t7TA3N4dieaRs0WLS5IH9+zFUGIyP3y5b1FRfusT\/mkqVLVsAt3HjxD+2UCqgoaEBtbW1XGi609LTNbpdmCEStsfrDZSwt7PDwkWLpNJi1OS\/586xkcWLw1BZWYni4mKcE21VVVX46cAB9dReVU9tw82brHft2s3akJCQEOTl50ulZc3q1fy7I0cy0dTUhA2x61lnZalkDy1GTUZ\/tRbDxJSOGjUK1tbWXKfi7x\/IMXd3d83GS2vK1tZWDKTvR0OEh4cbNdnR0YFQsTOQMVo+9GXHxW2RUX2Mmrx9+zZPWX19vV6hEVO5c+eO7Ane56ivKahvf3toZWUF8vLyjG49vfT74TwpPDM5UJg1NzeLvatEnCoXnshyURwmZiqVCoEi4\/H3938iS3Bw8LM1OWA8fSYpnackljbX3tLaeldGB47S0hLk5mrTNzrTdd+ZL04ouq6UlZdxXGOSMpgpMq+zsbHRlKKiItljYLgmEmrHkSMx9733ZQsQu\/5bvXfStYV8zJr9Fsc1JltamjlVShaJ7X1xjNHZStkzXRUMaW1t5WPycaA\/4cjhwxgxwoENLPv0MxkBZ0b0Lip0AaQMifrQrBIak\/n5eRg0aJC4bBXxvtnY2Cgjas4UnMaMGV7YvGkTb1kTRZIRGblCJBrqHPJh0KBsrG04PfPymoEP58+XEX2amhphMXgwYmM3yBYdk4kJCez+eZH5UB5J\/+o369bJKLDjhySOKxTLQQfAwYM\/szaWSRuDZqauro7rs2f5Yd68YK4bQpmRk7OzSK61SYnG5M4fd8DT0xM5x4\/zTVCp3MomMjIOc\/yDkGA4OTlxnUhPU98oKyoqZcuj4+PtLTbpEKm0XK6p4Wfu3rNXtqjRmDTGCy4uWBy2hOu02L+MWsV1YpW40Nvb2\/P6JVJTU7BJLAXD8r24BRreIk2Z3BIXhyFDLNF6V39H0ZjMzMzEUXFz02XMGFd89PEn6BIvoRH+kpYuI8Drr72Kt995Vyrg75Mn+RmGJTs7u8\/HZ8rkSxMnYs6cuVJp0Zj08\/VhI73rJiPjEOs\/\/8pF4ZkCrpeXV3DsrhipufjIlMptrB8X75kz+6zJJvGhGptqQmOSOk3z8ICr6xj4CsN2tnaIjo7h2LatW+Hs7MJ1okZs+vRxmbr5PYxAcTkLD18qlRp6ppWVlZFrCPAfnh\/yJ9VqDnIAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  , then what is the ratio of the 12<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> terms of the progressions?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Enter your answer as a decimal value, rounded off to two decimal places.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"0.5","CORRECT_ANSWER":"0.5","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The first term, seventh term and thirty-first term of an increasing arithmetic progression are in geometric progression. Find the ratio of the first term to the common difference of the arithmetic progression. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Four friends, Amit, Sumit, Praneet and Vineet, decided to run on a circular track, of length 2.52 km, at speeds of 21 m\/s, 23 m\/s, 18 m\/s and 19 m\/s respectively. If all the four friends started running from the same point at 8:00 a.m., then at what time after they start will all the friends meet for the first time at the starting point?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8:21 a.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8:42 a.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9:21 a.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>They will never meet at the starting point. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many three-letter words can be formed using the letters of the word \u201cEDUCATION\u201d, such that no letter is repeated? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>729\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>624\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>512\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>504\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>In a class, there are 40 boys and 32 girls. The average heights of the boys and the girls are in the ratio 10 : 9. Find the ratio of the average height of the class to that of the boys.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>45 : 43\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>43 : 45\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>45 : 47\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>47 : 45\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>At which of the following times will the angle between the minute hand and the hour hand of a clock be exactly 155<sup>o<\/sup>?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5:40 p.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4:50 p.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3:40 p.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2:30 p.m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the difference between the mean and the median of the observations <i>x<\/i><sub>1<\/sub>, <i>x<\/i><sub>2<\/sub>, . . . . ., <i>x<\/i><sub>n<\/sub> is <i>d<\/i>, find the difference between the mean and the median of the observations 5<i>x<\/i><sub>1<\/sub> + 8 , 5<i>x<\/i><sub>2<\/sub> + 8, . . . . ., 5<i>x<\/i><sub>n<\/sub> + 8.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5<i>d<\/i> + 40\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5<i>d<\/i> + 8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5<i>d<\/i>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhlAMrAHAAACwAAAAAlAMrAIcAAAAAADMAAGYAAJkAAMwAAP8AKwAAKzMAK2YAK5kAK8wAK\/8AVQAAVTMAVWYAVZkAVcwAVf8AgAAAgDMAgGYAgJkAgMwAgP8AqgAAqjMAqmYAqpkAqswAqv8A1QAA1TMA1WYA1ZkA1cwA1f8A\/wAA\/zMA\/2YA\/5kA\/8wA\/\/8zAAAzADMzAGYzAJkzAMwzAP8zKwAzKzMzK2YzK5kzK8wzK\/8zVQAzVTMzVWYzVZkzVcwzVf8zgAAzgDMzgGYzgJkzgMwzgP8zqgAzqjMzqmYzqpkzqswzqv8z1QAz1TMz1WYz1Zkz1cwz1f8z\/wAz\/zMz\/2Yz\/5kz\/8wz\/\/9mAABmADNmAGZmAJlmAMxmAP9mKwBmKzNmK2ZmK5lmK8xmK\/9mVQBmVTNmVWZmVZlmVcxmVf9mgABmgDNmgGZmgJlmgMxmgP9mqgBmqjNmqmZmqplmqsxmqv9m1QBm1TNm1WZm1Zlm1cxm1f9m\/wBm\/zNm\/2Zm\/5lm\/8xm\/\/+ZAACZADOZAGaZAJmZAMyZAP+ZKwCZKzOZK2aZK5mZK8yZK\/+ZVQCZVTOZVWaZVZmZVcyZVf+ZgACZgDOZgGaZgJmZgMyZgP+ZqgCZqjOZqmaZqpmZqsyZqv+Z1QCZ1TOZ1WaZ1ZmZ1cyZ1f+Z\/wCZ\/zOZ\/2aZ\/5mZ\/8yZ\/\/\/MAADMADPMAGbMAJnMAMzMAP\/MKwDMKzPMK2bMK5nMK8zMK\/\/MVQDMVTPMVWbMVZnMVczMVf\/MgADMgDPMgGbMgJnMgMzMgP\/MqgDMqjPMqmbMqpnMqszMqv\/M1QDM1TPM1WbM1ZnM1czM1f\/M\/wDM\/zPM\/2bM\/5nM\/8zM\/\/\/\/AAD\/ADP\/AGb\/AJn\/AMz\/AP\/\/KwD\/KzP\/K2b\/K5n\/K8z\/K\/\/\/VQD\/VTP\/VWb\/VZn\/Vcz\/Vf\/\/gAD\/gDP\/gGb\/gJn\/gMz\/gP\/\/qgD\/qjP\/qmb\/qpn\/qsz\/qv\/\/1QD\/1TP\/1Wb\/1Zn\/1cz\/1f\/\/\/wD\/\/zP\/\/2b\/\/5n\/\/8z\/\/\/8AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAI\/wD3CRxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRo0iTKl3KtKnTp1CjSp1KtarVq1hLAtjKtWvXrFjFKANLtqzZs2jTql07VEwmtnDjykVJC4LCeSyiHcSrdyBfin8V6iMUx29egoElJk44T0VXIAODcS28r3FXygYXMz6cmbNAzRBBExyMea9ngZK3lm7It\/Vpkbu6Bgi1Tx8VAAL6YhzsNUGy1x1FD9RXhfZn4KyRN+QNOaEYNJ8dc22+L7bq6JcRIxdukbvl6dgnJ\/\/XzW529NUQSRuOxl0j6faCCXdknhL+QesAVou2r1h5ZelbQfbddXedNs8Muu1inkPz4LDFKRPhBaFhE\/ZXIUL6KIKZhBtxuFBgg92xDy0J6GWbEZVxxh9gLFzoYYQtCqZhgReSaCIVKFr44l7SzTagXRPVJRAtKO4CZIcq+pfRjgblU9ySMcKo20E3iLGeQCGO+MCNKAbGH5NQXlgQiISI6KWSx10YTIlZVtRmiqeAOd+MFr2p0YocyakQLVvWhiODUeYZaGd9hXjmlJ2JSYuIla0g5kLBABFpQfnIoIUAv0FoGwAIbBFKPiyAodqmuX1XWINaELgpAmFkchiphd7\/hoAWlJGaDA6XZvqfaqiqKuuDfMFqWoWRJubahPoUYtyYh6VGXWW4Yhrjqp6CKmp+sJoKbar5YflrnK\/elpufnNKKmHRxCJuibqDRcuoKtLHzAF6miPtMqARSiuA+7CTwzL5OLvsQqJpaoReoU1o2mz5WCBOgs5tNaK2vuCGqbaXcFrapA57+pS6WVYQBgI8xQkzuuLsGAIq47Dk2LsYo7yoANLctaJAYVg4kT6DFenYslspSiPGoLAsLczTWNaeuwitXnLR2xAoYZbICh5cuy8MRIumRfqG7z9DdkuuAuSffe22tWA\/X8FZGPH3yjeXGwaGpYK+2KhhyW1qq1+42\/xpvA5bmu+lsR1smwCkMOwxA2wES1De\/D7z9deBb5SbsmtEMdqSxPrdYN6xG641045Kn3HRubqcZGRAeUn0u0RUTlA+CtqEnWHEHJqzCqXkNhmJ5ce4OOXu9y4d5Y4XJmzkhvwfg6vK\/s8k8vwAwui7y66q3ZjLCK+87vyRDM32\/iK7rbRzBcJ0suH3JKaFr7Aof7PgBBJ\/8lvMXdnz3W35fXijzi574fle9rOmvRIlJ32iCVhAFsuMGhaHFEXZGvJbdr3zzkIFAZiePGQxkUQVhh1fQQ4vm7AxCARsOFe73DCrYpTEvVI6X+Ac9fpXIgPvY3\/0GCD72+e+G3rILO\/8EcK8KBtCG0cjHCiH3myQucRcIFJ4KD9hEhKDhBsyKFfrUVwj2qe44FhzeEcmHPfj90In3ayL8ruQn3rVvULUxHgJfkw8VxAxLcgyj98YXtuvR8IwDUeILVRDDGvaLhyK8Q\/6q4xsaZo2AcaijxvLoQAiOCAcqEJHyroS92jFSkP8p5EDYYYEh3eGMZSxe9KC3iz6hhovLag0NxxhFN9ISjUzMyxrBeD6EfTGOB6xgQagmJIiwwy4ZKs1f3vcqZS1Tl4Na4xr1sQhXeZE4AHyVfARywme6iAVVnOYiQrGzT7zqSWMC0OL2UY4c4VFu6rTdPijoySzCyWPOPMzP1vP\/TGFSM5vXrMLzgGka4lVoF+6sDZ0Qg6BaYAIC6ztWP5u0r379y0TofEhgZofRZXF0OFXQ1JOwiZBDXe+cVQPjM6tItW6iNJAhjSMaerdEXmLzo2n6KDYX81EnWfMgmeBCZtRZpIS+J54EoWA\/mXkw3IVrQyjF6TxbVM\/XcSVHA+pjQcFko80Ic5oLdalepplR4qAwpjs950CTuSNQFdF8NtWQZlrT0IdSc6Ccg9BfdFoFO8TUSSL1qMEY5sWAedNjT2qMzXL4LH3gTWfQHCs0C+vUG0G1o1I9YVW71pUuIXWrcKTeHRtCi65w7S9K3Vey+tBPCgpEEZUz6PVUW4jn\/w2ofrlT6GU55NoRVe5eetUlbe8AKu5xpX6EKoiRFsjawxDJq9QDwGkPk1oTFaK5ko1Gb2FbsbkJ17rE1SWAnJcDE5WpIKWtWG+roz5PGYSaoDDEJ2ZwUQkpVZ\/A+Y6PAPQshyzXplWwHjsQILsnpTCFBzkhN2Mky+NWLb2lYjA4aYvd2y6LsK99Q4xEKN1dbWU2\/UpqXkJcmy7uaMADKYQ5y5eJGCT4NeXgInZHlNB76nMFRhzvp6LE4UE6mMS87LGIMejcGjsutusVyC4qMD2DQFi2dDXvbiXcMgfDlDYkDVgdj5uJ8gLTl77Fja6MpVrCEGwg3LXcIkDBhWTQd\/8G4fSMazmE4hKXYqQGzug+NCQvD49sx9m18JC4xk5YUmiZOG7wh3c8ISFbGMjmEzJkLVbkgzw5yVgaZ0TAjOCpBvcUYM4nhFyKuD8x1dNgblWLFhOYba5rzjTtEgtWjGrO5JPWCVGw7A7DDrlNlqDDCqQVKqRgCYUaoJ6W0IlsrJcTHlusbHT1splZIV\/2Wk6KeIMO9MEIYUQOfsUObW43SDs9C4TD4hnOQvMxbLh+bV8gwzKerWdP80H7vaZuEaxJYWuAiiaFGUqDZ9jtxUDCe118zeaUeloFTMAxqNAYSD0oRCle+1q26llPuE9xb14Ku+DkZtfA2\/1Limd8NPlqBpeL4DUPeKFc1l50NmcWyhfXdnw0eJa3IjvXFw1pNt+ewG+1Z35xP8F8z9rWhyG8fWZdw2mqB1NtFUCR89oEOKkP0IUboZbs18gDAY+90rUDVXMJc3zVBjoNwXl68MQQnOJcP7nRbfwoDP9DZBfPei4vx0iyQEd2RLmBtSGdp8rs8dF6pz41LQSADPwOHlw8BE27SqTEdQZmiOVbVzC+zXPDN0\/hJxXm4rXreP\/htvB4gYYWIHml0S\/GRpU38rljgKJawMBMk0UtcOSRg6R68OkPIekHixS5QC4RL8+4+oHNzcZ+fo9zenE9fhF5+homxjZClNYpysF56+dFibzLFPhzWKIkj7+VVRyIMqo0CTS43\/2TcDeaKX8bWfcF8\/x0\/BHLrpfNex7hxwdOLeJ\/0GcQvYV\/2hF9EaYb30N+IqeApJdd\/tNHiYd6A6d8eRYKz8cCqgdJCONai1dF6zWBkeR4gKcX7EB7+7D\/CDZQdAW4V0u0JslHG8snMLYxLhv4VRaYOcWBgK+1JbGXgEu1g65FgDs4fniRKUb4gPXmg38hfeXTZ+mhZ2fyaeTyAF0UbstzOOkFB8PmXZpyGw+wCA4Xhn\/mLQAwNpgxGNpnPl1oBWM2LWIoaoMjb7GEHKkRAJIAAAnQOorwAMIHRryhVWB4hVlIZWx4Cm+ock+3KViIbHVILmBXGovIhlOSh3uYANCgZ56Ef5pFCG0IJuP2bn3RVYByIR9jNSS1isURiF9UiJFIENzlhYyobHMIiTVjgyEzMj7EXWhzhh6WLqBYZePCJIYjW6d4EJjIhy\/yh4eGiKBYamfIIYP4\/4sLYipsKD75In9flCGEtmdbQYuJqFBANBjFNyTh+IVmJ4lhF0ehKIfAGG9WZ4fkYh4bQysc8obABXxoqIa6tohtxC8RZoV7FyXHSBwigpDziF5HEokKloiRqAhAwifK9WGZ+Ea1WDyHE4nUSAgUc43oko0eSYheNzUSKYvpiDjRqFzu5IoecWZIknknAZMIwQuPchHCkFIVQZMZwZMmYZNzURI+GZREWZRGeZTGt2g9eRvxiBKV15Tv1QgySRH6IJUX8ZSLtZNMmZUlUZVTiZQSsSlQCZZkWZZmeZZomZZquZZs2ZZu+ZZwGZdyOZd0WZd2eZd4mZd6uZd82Zd++f+XgBmYgjmYhFmYhnmYiJmYSvGUXuEVXKmYkBmZkjmZdjk\/ANBfG4EfQIQRp0aVHsk6SnJy1LYSCIUnHjGKGPKZcOdxUnIX6kQd+EEZWSVPlFmbtrmXnflBfJhDAPAAHilEfPiVH0SbFVF2Nwkowjkc7UhBmFYSqNkSk1IgCYMmEeF0BYUlM9JVtiE1GHmb3vmdebkzNAOVivA7kJFMtTEGDvFPJeUYhGMFmPAwpCM74vIbZ7NB4qJXlIMZlUcyn7Cf+Bk3aCgt9\/k1+ZlO15FBlwJqB6otjoN7cQKgBOE2lTcryuSeoACf8nmZlGIwr3M4\/WkclYcpejNmXqOgBFITocByGCM6JU5XmjzXOl0EnjRao\/9wOZrDNHVdcH8lUgsXgm6CswUus3BLdEguFEr8KDTdIz2QMWBJtKQiF1zPAKWDARnyQIGeQ6Vag0Q4hDmSFEdNqol5JGzZ9aXkk38QsqVXyp9FegAq8G2ElKR7xqaFsQ5z9E2gJj\/FE0xmekNb+j\/K9qebCSIr5H\/DYWJJkpw2uqiMKhe7FELIhZ1pAAca5XJQxC4HB1hfk4GEsld\/l1YH03l40Xih6k\/npVIs+nedloCCZ3UVQmbNpqoDV1Nf46FvMm5mtZCrylh+IXWAJoTUFU154Vof2Ezss1cZlVWQsQtHMBqEMEGf1ajSOq1BuU8hRJLHuRCBuEnyyIop9TP\/xqZjhViQcQhq8OZq9\/VpgnZkuMGIW6aUEEZsN2Rf6zhKWxE5OuVq3FqDC0kQ7aQzN0Q1O2KccBWvYIhTHbNqOsZGA7EO51hiXqR31DqxFJsWN7dBZABmlfF7BAGkWnVlfqFBIOutBoh2sSpMV7JevMUCpaB\/r6IFiKdvLpt50\/Z315dv7CIDfney7zVYtgqzvQpS9LiruxAEvdpRrGaycFKzOuhPiIqyzCImf9FrCNORxFmxWJu1TkGwBaFphroP+HBwDHGmmDNFKWIKnOok9AZGsKaS9te2k5YiIkhVitCkWCpMn3h0qiN9mjI9SRgji1chDLOz\/GiEEFK31EOn5P9hj1VHEFpnfMGUZOl6UhAChZ5megC1ga8KHIrAJrfBned2OFo7uqS7tX+XNdjikZ7bmxDxZAiKLfM2j4HIhvvoMbn4dC8ogMEFN2qYNUREZfX4YClJqGc4ix6KZryTkQw4krUCW5NIUt8BB391ddi0iiSHHcUIR6D4ViA4vMDriONku03ZnLw5MvHpL5yhObtauuzbvnQpDGubFvPgZXXiahQRnSyhJ+67v\/xbm1U5FwiFEacKGGJrElipk\/2bwAq8wAzcwA78wBAcwRI8wRRcwRZ8wRicwRq8wRzcwR78wSAcwh0iPMIkXMImfMIonMIqvMIs3MIu\/MIwHMMyDBQBAQA7\" style=\"width: 916px; height: 43px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"1176","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1176","UNIT":"sq.cm.","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Anil wrote down all the possible three-digit numbers with distinct digits on a blackboard. Of these numbers, Biswas erased all the numbers whose first and last digits were either both even or both odd. How many numbers were left on the board? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"360","CORRECT_ANSWER":"360","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost per ounce of an acid A has a linear relation with its concentration. If the cost per ounce of 98% A is Rs.590, and that of 20% A is Rs.200, find the cost per ounce of 56% A.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.560\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.470\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.380\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.340\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If there are five more men in a work force, they will take 16 days less to complete a job. Instead, if there are 12 more men in it, they will take 30 days less to complete it. Find the ratio of the number of men and the time taken (in days) to complete the given work.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhxgAuAPcAAP\/\/\/\/\/bkDoAOpDb\/\/+2ZgAAAAAAOv\/\/tmYAOpiYmEdHR1dXVzoAAGa2\/yMjI6enp8PDw93d3WlpaREREXp6euzs7ImJibW1tTQ0NNDQ0LZmAAA6kNv\/\/7aQkJCQ2\/\/\/25A6AABmtmYAANuQkLb\/\/2aQ2zqQkGY6kAAAZjo6kNv\/2wAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAxgAuAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmxADCBiAs6fPiwQKGOD5s6hRhwcQED3KtCnBpEudSjUKdapVjgWyat1aoGLVq2AvdvX4NWzHBFzTcmU5tmNZsxsV\/GzrVincjgsa5mX7MQCDrA02OngAAELWCBgfOIAwMIKEAhMoSKxgYUKBBRUOXkggsPLlzAAUaMWQsADjAoQ90v05GIAFCRklXDA9UAHn2Rkivq4QYQJngxQQW8jb+7cCxgtpo\/642udgC1nlDpSQ+jVE2gaxT1Rg4aB0ghhSH\/9f6OBwgccFugOIoFWgBPQOHrbVUGADBwAE7BckEJhlawvfdaYeXVwFOJB2jU0A2kSLAUBZahFI1pgFEgKwQHkO5IaQcnI9MNZyEsj1GGLLNUSXTkR1cB9B\/LX0n4EPwGZBavIhR5ACNEpkHQAPWBAfjxcMZNgE6hFUWWmnEcZeBBD8uGSIAnFnYkFVHeCBQS1u9AEIaYWA0IsFQaBABD9eZ6N7OXam1pkCxVhQa3sR1ORvBCFYZ5LrFRCBh1s5Jp2UDK12gAiBjUCCQFumpZ9ajKolEZgEkUldQQUehCAFdEp0QZwDJSAXpwMBmB2bB+K5ZJMFQRlakZTWWdCWDQT\/UMJBWWqUKFdeHgRpnWU+VIF2EOx1AasNVYBBZhV8VwGRdFK4ngO\/TSBcr5SaqicAy3kIgKqAttrWaluacMKK+\/W30q4DtQYRBeVNIF15WgUJEXpZVQgABQVoCEAGC0BWYb8FKKAhjgWJZpiS17J32LZ\/EuuqQM1pgMKhtJobaKPNXUSmTxtLBEGaIH1okIoaZfxReYjdRZAEKY\/UVVsBpKACCBaLpfLNpbUV1FAbmYzzzVmJ5PPPKg+NkdFEJ92z0kwLPRB9+uVHbtNUX0cQigKRXPXWUz5ll5Vch50clYQCYKjYaEP88ECwypo22i8f+CoI4k79NtffGiQxxXfDIa12QVr37TfMMtMs+N1BC7RzVIeLnXjjkCMN+eSUV\/5QQAA7\" style=\"width: 198px; height: 46px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='60' Height= '36' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADsAAAAkCAYAAAA3pUL9AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAUdSURBVGhD7ZlbLGVXGMfPdBono88qHJfGNIQgI+ZhOk1p6jLFyLSVtH3w4H5X16AlGaTEQeuSjkRVx7gUL+I6k+OWORovqHtoCIfhgWPMiLjfvu71nbXVPs45ktq2VPySFetbe21r\/9da37cuRwQ8MD8\/DzExMRAXF6czdXR00Df4Y3x8HKKjozW2x6aysjKsy4vYiooKKC4uRtG60tbWFn2DP\/Lz86GmpkZje2xaWVnBuryIjYiIgJmZGWoJx9HREQQGBsLa2hot0c25xZKGAgIC4ODggJYIh0KhgJCQEGqdzbnFyuVySElJoZawNDc3Q3p6OrXO5ljs3t4exMfHgb29PXzi5AQ9PX\/SJ7opKCiAqqoqzB8eHmJPe3p6HidfX1948qQEn\/NNZmYmNDU1UUtFclLScdv+\/gGwublJn1CxZO7HY+SKh4aGBvjA3Bxu3dKHxcVFrKSL8PBwmJycxPwfTKAwMDBAPwoODobQ0FAQiUSQI83F53xDOnZhYYFaAN1dXWBnZ4dtk1RUVITaWFAsGZF2WTsWEJqZ3iIfOcaEdV0Qf\/Xz84P9\/X20K589g+XlZcwTiB+bmprC\/KtXtIQ\/VldXsVPJt7N4MaP51+AgtU6j0Wd\/LS2FR4++4PwjTRB\/TWKmjTbKfyuD+\/c\/pha\/dDGjmJqaSi3Vt5ABMpZIIIpZd092OgtHLFkHW1pawNLSkvnbSku1Q\/y1urqaWqdxd3OF3Lx8avFLXl4e1NXVUQvQ5dra2uA7RiiKNjaG2VkFfaqCI1apXIZcqRSMjIzg5s13sfdYWltbMSCcJDIy8thf1Vl9\/RpMJCYwxyzq6pBpTwKHtsS6BQvZNOTmcv0+KioKd0+aGB0ZAbFYDx587kFLVGicxktLS\/Cevj58+ZUPOnhaWhp4eHhgj5GGCez6qv5hLL+Xl8O9ex9Ri0t\/fz++qy3J5T1Yb2NjA2JjY8HNzQ3bJlOVsL6+jvXICqINaU4O3LjxDnYei0axhAfu7vCZiyuKHR4exjJvb28wMTHBfG9vLyQnJ2NeE+R9qZYoTGIB+VBtiY0V29vbMDo6inlHR0ewsrLCfF9fHyQkJGBeG91dnWBmZgZ7JwZDq9gPb9+GX9TWx4mJCexhmUyGvlpZWUmfcHnzZhU7RaGYoyXnZ2BgANvu7OyExsZGKCnhftuKUsmZZWFhYfD4MXfDgWJ3d3fA1cWFWYT9oba2FoKDgpieS8QK6pDRtba2xv3w9PQ0LeVSUPAz3LnjQC3+IBsFCwsLbHtoaIiWqnBmNkIkKJUyK4mUiTtkz6DuYiiWTJuKp08xlJOpdzIwqcOOrq2tLS05zYvnz0Heo\/I7Ppmbm8O2yaxRXxZJUMrK+hGys7OZ7++mpVy0TmNdBDEjn5GRQS1hIefTxETNs+4s\/pPY\/yvXYq8qokFm45zDLMDEsa9yKiwsBNHU1BQe6656Iufea5+9qlyLvaoIKpZcWPv4+IC5uTk4O38KL1+qjmxCIZhYcja9e9cRQpnTCPn14H0DA9DTE8PYmO57Lj4RTCw5XGRlZVMLYGRkGDf16Rnc24+LRDCx6r\/z7OzsoNi8\/J9oycVzaQFqiNm5icVixo\/5v2bVxqWJ9X74EFK+\/4FawnApYuvr6\/Fe+uCMe2m+EVxsu0wGXp5esLv3783gyZ8oLhJBxfbI5eDk5ASzs7Nor719i5fdy0ol2heNYGL\/npwEQ0NDkEgk4ODgADY2Nri5+Pqbb2mNiwbgHwd81AJHzXsaAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  .\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='60' Height= '36' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADsAAAAkCAYAAAA3pUL9AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAUlSURBVGhD7ZlpSFxXFMcHUiKxKfFLGqxGExSLIkajNJ9qSk2sOkraCq2N\/aDiEhUV9\/VDtUR0rAvSKi5FcanRthKXLyMoGYsLCMZgUOsGVokbuIDbuJ2+c+aOM2PnqY1vRmr9wcV37r1v7vvfe87dFIEATE1NQVRUFERHR\/OmgoIC2N3dZW8Iw9bWFqSlpWltTz2VlZVRfUHEVlZWQmFhIYnmS7Ozs6y2cAwODkJERITW9tTT4uIi1RdEbFhYGExMTDBLf0gkEmhoaGDW8Zxa7MrKCgQEBAjuoichNDQURkdHmXU8pxYrk8kgKSmJWfpjbW0N\/P39YXt7m+Ucz4FYfCkmJhrs7OzgY2dn6Oz8g5UcTX5+PlRXVzNLQVRkJHh4eFAKDQ37Vx90Urq7uyEuLo5ZADk5EhCLxQft+vj4QHx8Auzs7LAaTOz+\/j7E0MwVA42NjXDL3ByuXDGEmZkZqnQU6ErDw8PMAmh6\/hzs7e0hKCiIUklpKSsRlqKiIigvL6fnP0dG4MaNG+Dr++1Bux8YG8PDh65UroTE7u3tQZu0jTKQ5qYmEIlEMPj6NcvRDsarn5\/fQe9h3D5wcYGx8XGydUlsbCz09vbSs1Qq5Ua6h56V3Lv3EdT+UscsBVpjtrSkBB49+pw64SgwXhMSEpgF0NLcTJ1kxnlGXFw8LC0tsRJhwfUV43V9fZ3laDLGTVpmZmawurrKchRoiN3Y2ICWlhawsrLi\/rayXH4wXmtqapil2Fzg+yEhISTawtIS3rwRfn0dGBiASG5e4OP7jAwufj2ZpUJD7MLCPEiys8GY8\/dLl96B9vZ2VgLQ2toKGdyPqBMeHq4Rr+r09vSQ4G8eP2Y5CnB+wBHhS5ubm6ymgqGhIUhNTYX5+XmWAzQhYkfz4eToyA1CLbNUaHXjubk5eNfQEL740ps+Drdk7u7u9PG1tYofUa6v6rPdYRLj4+Hq1fe4WFaFA3oPztb4rraUm5vHagJUVFSAl5cXtYtuqyQlJQU6OjqYpcn42BjcNL3JfZ+mCyNaxSKfubrCpy4PSCy6DYINm5qa0nNXVxckJibSMx+\/\/\/YrFxIf0m+og0sRX1LvPNwOYl5xcTEJnp6epnzslOXlZXo+DLqwh4eYWZrwirW0sIAffypilgJ0KWwUZz+M1aqqKlaiAF1NXZgv58J5efzudlJwQjIyMoLg4GBydfzLh+Pdu9x3aa77SkisXL5FSwa6Sl1dHQQFBnJTu2rBVgdH19ramvbDY5zLqGN\/5w7cun2bW\/9+pvhOTk5mJacHDxrY0Tk5ObzxOvCyH65dM6IQ0waJxSWmkosPnAiysyUaE9NhlKNra2vLclT09fWRyGxukpN1drJcYZDL5bRxwLaxHW2g2z97Vs+sf8LrxkcRyI18eno6s\/QHnkvd3NxI+NvwVmL\/q1yIPa+I+vv7ISsrCzIzM891wjswEZ708Vh33lMTnuTYCP8vuBB7XrkQqyvwcO\/t7Q3m5uZw\/\/4n8OKFjJXoB72JxatPJydHCHnyhDb171+\/DpcvG3D72aPvuYREb2LxcPH0aSazAF69GqBN\/XfpmrcfukRvYvGGQh08o9KR7YdclqN7zmyCesnt3AwMDLg4\/ovl6J4zE+vl6QlJySnM0g9nIra+vp7upXePuZcWGr2LbZNKQewhBvm26v8\/hy\/kdIVexXbKZODs7AyTk5Nkrywv053S\/MIC2bpGb2JHhofpDsnExAQcHBzAxsaGNhdffe3DaugagL8BgaLTgVoBJiwAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  .\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='60' Height= '36' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADsAAAAkCAYAAAA3pUL9AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAUrSURBVGhD7ZlrSFxHFMdNP7gYaIiFKEQxMQ8sKX4Q83ntF5tWU1IQaqkKWY2PJGviY01bJdGYauMLVIpU\/KpBtxDybGJRmzTkg6uNjwgpKj6qYnzGRwyuMf47Zzxrdtm7ukZ2FfEHg\/fM3Hud\/9w5Z87MusBOxsfHkZKSguTk5FXLzZs3+Qnn0NHRgcTERMW+mEpFRYW8126x9+7dQ3Z2Nvr7+1ct09PT\/IRzKCwsRFVVlWJfTGVsbEzea7fYtLQ0NDY2srU1WFpaQkxMDKamprhmdewS+\/btW2g0GszOznLN1qC3txdxcXFsrY1dYru7u5GQkMDW1uHOnTvIyspia23sEltTU4P8\/Hy2AJ0uFSEhISvl+4gI\/HL9Oreun5mZacSeOQN\/f398ceIE2tvbuWV1KIbcvn2brWV+uHRppV8aTTTm5ua4xU6xly9fRm1trbyur6\/DJ+7uOH1ag9jYWMTHx8PNzQ1abaJsXy9v3rxBTHQ0rl7Nhl6vh\/vevfDw8MT0zAzfYRuawgMDA2wBDfX1csCoX1RKSkqkX5uwSyy9dHBwUF7ra\/To7OyS1yaOHD6MpqZmttbH5OQEGhr+Ygv4tbQULi4uGH75kmuUmZiYkMHp3bt3XAOEiq\/5z7NnbFmzptihoSE5SraoffgAx44dY2vjZGVmChFn2LJNvfiKGRkZbAGPHz+Wg7Tfywtase6OjIxwy3vWFHv37l1cu3aNLWsiIyNw4eJFtj6cGTFtb9yowpGjR8USZ+Ba2xQUFKC6upotyJl3\/\/59XBBCpej9+9HT08uty1iIffLkifTP+fl5rgGui8BDvqSE0TiPgwcOwmBo4pr3kK9QcLBVzP8HQb535coV6bMf79mDtrY2boFMGswDJKHVamX2pES7eFalcsWJL7\/immVWxJKo0NBQOSrmLz579iy6uix91MRDMYX9\/D5ly5LJyUkkiOAVLYKPUvmtvJzvtOTfFy+wS\/QhJVWHhYUFJCUlITg4WPaLpipBs4DeQe22yBN6du36SA6siRWxra2t8i+N2O7du+XIUxJBLzUPAuZERUYi8YLyFKYvS52xVRYXF\/lOaz4TMSAmJlYmM6ZlKDAwUAysn7w2GAxITU2V17ZoEKuGj48PFsQ7TFj57PDwsBzFsrIymUzodDpuscRoNMLX11dxCm8EGgSPfR64dcty\/Wxubpb9qqurE223ZP\/MGRsdlYNjgpKgzEzLhEMxQNHa6enpiby8PFRWVnKtJb\/ra3BA+OtG6evrQ1CQGufPa2XACQ8PR05OLrdaQonCoUOHcO7cObS0tHDtMkFqtQxK5cI9qN\/JySkW4glFsaavS8kCLT1K\/C38548HD9j6cCipoK9Ey0hRURGePn3KLdbQwFC\/vL29rVyLglJOzs\/Izc0Vy1ID11qiKJZIT09HVFQUW1sH2p\/acq21sCl2O7Ijdrvi8kwkzpRQkGNv51JcXAyXzs5OeUi23Qvte3d8druyI3a74lSxdGAdFhYmcuoDIh\/+HI8eLW\/ZnIXTxL5+\/RrHjwciXuxGSktLxc5mH1xdVXj+XHkD7gicJpbOjMx3M21trTKpz7qazTWOx2liaXdjDh0OkNiCwiKucTybFqBaROamUqmEH\/\/HNY5n08R+ffIkfvwpnS3nsCli6eeUU6e+waKNsy1H4XSxf9bWIjQkFMaF9yeD5j9ROBKniqWjHLVajZ6eHmlPvXolD7tHRkel7WicJpbOg+kQz8vLCwEBAfInE0ouvg3\/ju9wNMD\/CpTS\/SwFxloAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  .\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='63' Height= '37' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAD8AAAAlCAYAAAD1EjEiAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAWLSURBVGhD7ZlrSFRpGMe12tT95H4IFO1Di\/ohFaGiddLMWyJtCi21UFkqkdoWhWLrDcXVSFfMdNXUpUI3Mg1XXM1oU2ktyKD6VHgpL7uOs+s9vIGm9d\/3fecZnbEzMxp6BrIfvHCe55w55\/2\/l+d5zhkzrBCFhYU4d+6cwRYTE4PW1lb6xepw\/\/59nDlzRvL5mpaVlYX3799jxcSHhoaiq6sL3d3dBttqw8U1NzdLPlvTlEqluHZFxN+9exfJyclkmY6hoSGEh4eTZZwVEX\/x4kXcvn2bLNPBl3xSUhJZxlkR8SdPnhTLydRkZGSgoqKCLOPoiM\/JyYGXlxf2BwXh8eMW8hpmYGBALDUeQDhPWloQGRmJEydOiHbq1CnExsaio+OVOL+aREREoLOzkyxgamoKZ8+ene\/L5dzc+X5y5sVfSE\/HwYOHUFBQAFsbG1hYWKK9o4PO6ufevXtITEwUx7Nv3+KbnTvh6uqKwMBA0bZv3wYzMzOoVP+Ka1aL4eFhhIWF4d27d+RRrwQXF5f5vpSWltEZNUI8H40bN24IB+dh81+iw3V36smjH\/6AyspKcdzW1opcNrra\/JKXBx8fX7IM08EGe3p6hqzl0dDQgISEBLKAQbYi\/f38yZJGcs83sMDh6OiIN2\/ekEc\/fL\/zFMfRHnUNCnd3FBWXkGUANgFeu71Y7Oghx\/LIzMzErVu3yAIS2UDwCTxw4DvU1taRVxcd8XNzc2L0\/fz8UF6+cCN98NTC87v2PtKmt\/cf2LAt1M9mwSjsHj7ePujp+Zscy4NPwuvXr8nikf9PEfkdHBzEIERERNKZBXTEDw4Oih98sWEDrK2tWbHwkM4Ak5OTqKqqwlu2rzXw1KLZ71Jcys7GHm9vsowTsDeABdBBsvRTU1PDBraXLGB0dFTsdz55UiQkxIsBKC37jTxqJJd9e1sbvrSywm6vPcJuamqCv7+\/uEE2E6SBLzVDqYUv+cIrRWR9yPPnz0Rm0DQ7OzscOXJ03q6p+YOuVMMjeUhICDZu3IiAgADyAo2NjYiPjydLGlcW+HZ5eJKlRlI8J\/T4MWzZ8rU45jfnNTnvkBUblJGREeFfnFq06WMlpK2NLf7r7yfPh4yPj6O9vV3d2IAr3BVioDU+vq20efHihShdq6urxUQ8ePBA+PkklJeXi2N9\/Hj+PBS7PMhSo1f8t\/v24dCh78lS08+ErFu3DnFxccI2tN8v51xiNYN65SyVvf57l5wS3dzc4OzsLI6joqLw6pXhOoLrKSn5lSw1QjzfKykpKSwPloqZvH79GhQKhWRHeEwwNzdHcXEx0tLSyKsLHxAX1rH8gkLyLAH2mx3bdrDnqzOHMR49eiRmP4+l0ujoaJ39rlKpxDJPTf2Jpd92sVUj2KpdPFHz4kNDj8PDw0MEjtTUVFE0SMEDn62tLdavXy9yqxTjY2MIORoiqr8lwzpWVFTEttQoOYwTHBwsBmDxJExMTCCKieUT+MPp0ygr0y1uNOhd9obIz8+HpaXl8sStAi9fvmSVqAXL47XkWR4fJZ4XM5p3YlPDU55UcbUUPkr8p8LaFj87OysqpLXWxlhQNuMFDH8f51F+LTX+ncGM5z59hcqnDNf8OeCtVT6LNxX8+8H09DRZ8mMS8U1NjXDeulWUpps2bcIVVtObAtnF9\/Up4ejgIN4K+fs4\/9rLX04aGhrpCvmQXXx9fT1u3lz48KBU9grx0dEx5JEP2cUvrilmZmaE+J+zssgjHyYNeJwnLY9hZWmFPpWKPPJhcvG+vj5IT79AlryYVPy1q1dx+PBhsuTHZOJ\/r6oSn6G0kfsdwyTi6+\/UwdPTE729SvBXav4p\/AJb+nJ\/HZJd\/LOnT\/GVtTXsN28W\/6A6OTnB3t4e+4N0V8HqA\/wPct\/zvrJBrxAAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the remainder when the product 567890 \u00d7 567892 \u00d7 567894 \u00d7 567896 \u00d7 567898 is divided by 11.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"6","CORRECT_ANSWER":"6","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the last digit of the sum 0! + 1! + 2! \u2026\u2026\u2026 77!?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"4","CORRECT_ANSWER":"4","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the distance between the lines 3<i>x<\/i> + 2<i>y<\/i> + 7 = 0 and 6<i>x<\/i> + 4<i>y<\/i> + 15 = 0.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='20' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAgCAYAAAASYli2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKJSURBVEhL5ZY9aFpRFMe1oAQc7JBGAs0QXFIyphGz1i8ytskQF4eQYC2ocXRKbAa3mDnQDDbaNBYNtk0gERtwcxEVqhCrCBGxKGggDQHNv9777ksofrwH6VL6gwvvnHv58c575x2eBCIpnJ\/D4XCgWq2yTH9ECSsXF3g2NQWJRIpa7SfL9kdQGAwEMDIygunpaUilj5DL59lOfwSFpycn+HZ2hi+fo907lDxcyPMhGPjfhMHA3t8V7r33U+H3XI5l+iNaWK\/XkUwm8ev6mmX6I1ooln9AWCgUEAwGEeh+Yg9dBwcHkCQSCVitVqyurg5cNpsNLpdr6CKTyG63iy853+2\/bDY7cF10JxJBlNDj8WBubg6Li4sD1\/r6Oj0rSmgymZATaGgeQWGtVoNOp8PNzQ3LDEdQGI\/HaUliERRubW3B7XazSBhBocViQSQSYRHQarWQSqVQKpVY5k+GCm9vb2E0GvGjWKTx4WEEj5VKKBQKyOVyvLa9QafToXs8Q4Xlchl6vZ6KG40GHV8vXy2gUqng6Ogrjff3P7LTHEOF4XCYlky4urpCLBbD5eUljclbJ8J3u7s05ukRkmfEQ5rV6\/WyiKPdbmNlZQVPRkehNxhZ9p47YSaTgcFggFqtvus5s9mM4+Njes1DBu3a2lq3lRYwPj6OUOgT2+G4E\/r9fvh8PloGmRoE0tCksQeh173A04kJFnH0lKzRaKDVaunHPj8\/z7Lc78jy8jKKxft2MS8tYWxMxSKOHmE0yv0hOJ1OOpZ4yJ2S\/OysBqenMWxvc9W83dxkJzh6hOShT05O0sOhUIhlOdLpNJ7PzEDZ7UWVSoWNDQ\/buadHSNjZ2YFMJkOz2WQZsQC\/Ac2D6ZkUXSWYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='27' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABsAAAAhCAYAAAAoNdCeAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAMcSURBVEhL7ZdNSBtBGIYDoh70pIgBG2laW7xrNDWKaDZb619atHiIRQ9WjPbgRdBTerKhTXtQG63FgxVpAq03UfAn4EGioDlZJB6EBKrGH4yg4u\/bncnURGPNutZL6QND9p3Z7LPLlx2+yCCRz7296OzsYkkckmR2mw0xMTEwVL9gM+K4lmx\/fx\/awkLExcVDnpyMiopKtiKOa8m2trZgbGiAx+NFeVkZOB3PVsQhuWacthA6\/jFL4pAs03Ha\/7IzJMuyVJnIylazJA7JMuvHLlit3SyJQ7JMCv+w7PT0FAcHB7c+Dg8PIRseHgbP8+A47lZHmbC9ycjmura2htXV1T+OjY0NHB8fSx7E4fP5xNXs6OgIra2tqK+vlzQ6OjrodUTJBgYGkJeXB7vdLmlMTU3R64iSNTY2oq+vjyXpiJKVlJRgdnaWJelElK2vryM\/P58W+aZElDkcDuj1epZuRkSZ2WxGW1sbSwG6rVaYTK9ZCrC05MbLujpoNBo0Nb0SWgcPWwkSUWYwGDA0NMQS8KW\/HzKZDEVFT9gMsLy8jPj4OCiV99DS0oJUhQIKRSotQShXysgLWVBQgJ8rK\/Rde\/ZUj9jYWCQmJqKy8jk7C7DZvuKuUilsDj6aySZAbujb9+BNEq6Uud1uutUQ\/NvbqBaecnFxUahheVhndXJyQj9JB2Y2v0FCQgIWFn7Qud+ck+3s7GBubo4lYHBwELW1tSwF0ek4oSUIb+Omp6chl8vpU5G6XeRMNj4+DpVKRU\/0er10rrm5WWixO+lxKDyvu1RG9lGXy4VPPT2IiorC23cWthLgTDY6OoqxsTEqM5lMdK64uBhOp5Meh3JRRmq7t7fHUoBH6mykPXjIUoCwmlVVVSEpKQmbm5vQarXw+\/1sJchF2Yf3FqSk3MHublCYlnYfOTkalgKEyUjNyNMZjUbU1NSw2fOohbvOVgc7K9f8PP1ORkYmuoR\/NpzQ5pE8OelgZwQIkxFyc3Ppye3t7WzmPBaLhY5QZmacKC0tRXp6uvAD0mFiYoKtBLlUNjIygujoaOGnu8Bm\/gbALzKhdlqXM4MhAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='33' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACEAAAAhCAYAAABX5MJvAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAO5SURBVFhH7ZdLSFRRGMdHFEuUkeyhqDsXtUwnDcnQmbHSAScVX8yguTIq0pUPEDVBMDeCkwsXCrrJSFEzy2whZJqP8VFoSrbwgS1KFNTQfP475\/PcGUeFuDMDRfiDA\/P\/vrnn\/u893\/nuvQo4gdraWlRVmYSSj8MmWltb4O7ujrQ0g4jIxyETaakpUCq94e\/vj\/j4BBGVj90mdnZ2UFJSgpmZGcTf1kOt0YqMfJxSE9FaDTTaaKHk4xQTN6K1JyaIf8JE6BUVQlRXhJKPU0w0NNSjvr5BKPk4xYSjnJiQUCwuLmJoaAiDg4N\/ZQwPD0PR2dkJnU6HmJiYvzISEhL+k5pob29HRkYG0tPTZY\/KykqawyETe3t7CA8Ph8lkQmNjo+zR09ND8zhkYn5+HpGRkULZj0MmOjo6kJSUJJT9OGSirKwMhYWFQtmPQyaMRiOampqEsh8bEy9fttPejYiIwMPsbCwvL4vMUXhRarVaTE9PiwiwsbEOg8GAyclJERGvgcXFNGdiYiIGBgZFxorFxLPGp1AoFMjKuovq6mqcP38OISEqrK+vi3\/YsrCwQEXJT8L5ubYGdVQkzdHfP0Cxra0taDUaeHp60nY0Gg1wc3PD2MePlJewmNDHxeHGzVtCAQP9H2jCrq63ImJLW1sbUlNT6beZtf2AAH8EBgbC1dWVPQbMFP\/x4ztUKhVev+4kzXFj+YfZOULtYzHBr3hzc1Mo4EVbK5kYHR0TEVuKiopQWlpKv7u63qC8\/DE+T0zAxcXl2FvO6Xn3DqdPn0JLS6uI7HNsYf7a2MAFthxx+tsiAkxNTWFubk4oICUlhbrlQSbGx8n4YRP8AnW6WMpdi7guolaOmPjG1vrSpYsIZvWwurpGsbq6Onh5ebEaCSG9u7uLqKgozM7Okpb4xNb6OBM729uYYHepu7sbvr6+uHf\/AStskWTYmBg2m3Hu7Fm2Q2KxxQ6UMLN4c3MznWBkZARLS0tQq9W0Qw5y2ATP8+I8SOmjEijYkkkFzbGYmP7yBd7e3sgvKBCRowQFBdHDqq+vj317pomolcMmvrLt6+fnh1cHCjPzTgbOnPGhuylhMXE1NJQmSE5OZt+V8dDr9TTM7KVDoqamBh4eHsjMzERFRYWIWhnhLyhsjvfv+0jzvhEcfJlOyo\/Nz8ujfJXpCeUlLCZ4+81mDYo\/YnknlMbYmHV3rKyswMfHhybq7e0VUSu8nnJycmxqZY31j9zcXISFhVEdPT+mwx4pzD9RzLqfUqkUyhkAvwE6HiqMUTjTZgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='35' Height= '34' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACMAAAAiCAYAAADVhWD8AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOzSURBVFhH7ZhfSFtXHMfDBCMimKibdjpwGGVT6cDVgaJSnzRGG4cx7dToHnRKiyCVFtSRFGldnVhoQTvFB8E\/2\/z7orZPIv4ptkxwc6158UWxaFOQVq2o6HfnnPubMS7p4OZCffADB87vd+49fO45J+feExUUor+vDzbbLYrkoYjM9NQUtFoNEhO\/oYw8vJLZ3d3FlcuX4ePjw2S0+PpCIrXIwyuZt2\/ewGQy4Y+5OZjy8qDTRVOLPBRbM\/rMzNMjk6XXn8m45VTJpF+8iHPnPqVIHorJVFZWwmjMpUgeiskowZmMJ06XzPDwMMrKyj54KS8vh2p+fh5dXV1eld7eXgwMDMgu\/f396O7uVm6a1tbWsLy8LKusr6+LPhSR6ejoQGxsLPRsF5ZT+DRxFJExm83o6emhSD5eyxwcHCAtLQ12u50y8vFaZmlpCampqTg8PKSMfLyW4VsD\/9pTAq9l6urqYLVaKfIOjzI3b95Ac\/M9ijxjNBoxNjZGkURFRTmT\/JEiicHBQSQkJCAqKgpFRRasrr6kFiduZdrb2qBSqXDpfz4J9vb2kJKSgpWVFcrwkaoV9xaXfE8ZoO\/330TOZMrHg\/v3ERYaii++jMXOux26QuI\/MosvXoijh6+vLwoKCynrHr57p6enizoXio+PQ2BgIAICAtje8YPIc27ZrNBnZVEEPJmZFnLzf\/5FGQkXGf6kn0VE4OrVa\/jq\/Hnk5n5LLe7p7OxESUmJqD9\/\/jd7v1SInTgiPFxMhTu2trZQff06QkJC4HC8pqyEi0xhQQF00dJ3bIxOB+MJmdnZWcyxM9K\/VFVVoampiSInIcHBsFiKKXLyy8OHCGVTxEelra2dsk6OZH7t7YFa7cfeE69E\/HlkJEz5ZlHn1NTUiE4i2MjxjY6Tyc5Kk5OTon6cj9lTu5Ox2xcxPj6O0tJSaDRaTE3PUIvEkYyfnxofsbXC10BSUhITUyMoKAgGQza2t7cxMTGB1tZWITQ6OiruSU5OxsbGhqgfx5PMcYLYcfjkyB\/JtLS0oKGhQYwAL3whRsfEiBw\/U3P29\/fFXHPhhYUFZGRkiPxJTsoUWyy48l0BRRJajYatK1dhlzVznE9Yh4bsHIqc1NfXi9HhL0cu7Q41+yXm5Tl35bs\/NYh7rDYbRkZGkG0wiPjps2d0hYRHGXN+Pmpr6yhy4nA44O\/vLzobGhqirCuXcnJw+\/YdiiR+bmxEWFiY+LciLi4ejx49phYnHmXeR3V1tdiHNjc3KaMEwD95UpzjEegCygAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A building of height 20 m has a pole on top of it. A person standing at a certain distance from the foot of the building observes that the angle of elevation of the top of the building is 30\u00b0, whereas the angle of elevation of the top of the pole is 45\u00b0. What is the height of the pole?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 <img Width='18' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAASCAYAAAC9+TVUAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIQSURBVDhPjZK9a5pRFMZf8GNwaQahrUszuDhJCnYwXdJBIZLS6CBiXFKxrfoHpBLBLUWQJGIml7ShIVVQpxREBHVIFwmFBj\/AbI1fi7qIH\/jUe7w1aclr+4MXzvOcy3PvPfcVsIButwuPx\/PPb2FIPp+H2WxGLpcT\/QqFwuIQn8+HSCTClTgLQ2w2G7LZLFfiiIYMBgMYjUY0Gg3uiCMaUq1Wsb6+jslkwh1xREMSiQScTidXM25ufqJcLmM0GnNnhmhIIBBAMBikejQc4vX2NqRSKRQKBZ4sL+P8\/Cv1GKIhdrsd6XSaav\/uLgRBwOfTU9RqNZim15TL5Wi12tS\/N4QN1WAwoN2eLTrY38fOznuqGd8vLyn04uIb6XtDKpUKTCYTV7f0ej0Ui0W83NjA6upz9Pt98oXxeIxYLAa3243h9O6MeDwOl8tF9V2OjiJQKpV0ir29D9ydhkSjUWi1WmqkUiky\/X4\/QqEQ1XfpdDrTObQQPjyk9cfHH8kX2BHZv6BSqaDX68lkQ81kMlQzms3mfD6\/efzoIdbWXlA9nwl7TpZeKpVgsVhQr9d5B3im02Fl5SlXbDZdeu43b9+RnoewnWQyGQ3U4XBwd8bJySfawL61hXA4DI1GgwdLS6hdX1P\/j9exWq202Ov1cueWL2dn0E1PpFar8WpzEz+urnjnrxB2FYlEgmQyyZ3\/AfgFtjILyBAmIEUAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 ( <img Width='17' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAASCAYAAABSO15qAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHuSURBVDhPjZO9a1pRGMYvuFynBtJdSE1uwDqkY0hGEQRdxEUFaUAcXMTUbtJ2EwQxWcXBxRaFBNLNG0EHQfwH\/JgipvT6gYOiEVGfeF5PMCn3Sn9w4TzP+\/KczytgB4VCAcFgcOe3M8DtdiObzaJcLqt+lUpFO6Df78NqtXKljWZAtVqF0+nkShvNgHQ6jVAoxJU2mgHhcBipVIorbTQD2PJrtRpXwGKxQKPRwOPjH+5sUA2YTqewWCwYDoek72UZBoMBol4PvajH54sLPD3NqKYaUK\/XYbfbsVqtMBgMIAgCzs7P0Wq18PvujvS37z+oVzUgn88jEAjQuNPpwOv1otlskWaYP5pwenpGY9WAaDSKRCLB1Zb2wwMymQz23+\/j5uaWPGG5XJIZi8XIYHg8Hsjrfb9mNBrh08kJLf\/g4AMUpUu+kMvlYDabqcCWy7DZbGi32zR+gU3U6\/XWW2lCko5weHhEZySMx2PM53PodDrE43G6AfaEWZExm80o7EUzfv3M0oR\/FWV7Bi6XCyaTiX4Sn8\/H3c0VsmZZvucOEPlySd5kMt0GlEolMh0OB5LJJHexbprg+FjCu709OtjL9QtlfZHIV6q\/uQVJkqhYLBa5s6HbVeD3+2E0Gum8rq6veeWfADazKIr0bP8P4BnY6smCUCgZFgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  - 1) m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 ( <img Width='17' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAASCAYAAABSO15qAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHuSURBVDhPjZO9a1pRGMYvuFynBtJdSE1uwDqkY0hGEQRdxEUFaUAcXMTUbtJ2EwQxWcXBxRaFBNLNG0EHQfwH\/JgipvT6gYOiEVGfeF5PMCn3Sn9w4TzP+\/KczytgB4VCAcFgcOe3M8DtdiObzaJcLqt+lUpFO6Df78NqtXKljWZAtVqF0+nkShvNgHQ6jVAoxJU2mgHhcBipVIorbTQD2PJrtRpXwGKxQKPRwOPjH+5sUA2YTqewWCwYDoek72UZBoMBol4PvajH54sLPD3NqKYaUK\/XYbfbsVqtMBgMIAgCzs7P0Wq18PvujvS37z+oVzUgn88jEAjQuNPpwOv1otlskWaYP5pwenpGY9WAaDSKRCLB1Zb2wwMymQz23+\/j5uaWPGG5XJIZi8XIYHg8Hsjrfb9mNBrh08kJLf\/g4AMUpUu+kMvlYDabqcCWy7DZbGi32zR+gU3U6\/XWW2lCko5weHhEZySMx2PM53PodDrE43G6AfaEWZExm80o7EUzfv3M0oR\/FWV7Bi6XCyaTiX4Sn8\/H3c0VsmZZvucOEPlySd5kMt0GlEolMh0OB5LJJHexbprg+FjCu709OtjL9QtlfZHIV6q\/uQVJkqhYLBa5s6HbVeD3+2E0Gum8rq6veeWfADazKIr0bP8P4BnY6smCUCgZFgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  +1) m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The simple interest accrued on an amount of Rs.30,000 at the end of four years is Rs.7,200. What would be the compound interest accrued (in Rs.)<\/font><font style='font-family:Rupee Foradian;'> <\/font><font style='font-family:Arial;'>on the same amount, at the same rate of interest, at the end of two years?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"3708","CORRECT_ANSWER":"3708","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Each of A, B and C have some chocolates with them, such that the ratio of the total number of chocolates with A and C to those with A and B is 5 : 4. If the ratio of the total number of chocolates with B and C to those with C and A is 6 : 5, which of the following is the ratio of the number of chocolates with B and C?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 : 7\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 : 6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>An isosceles trapezium is circumscribed about a circle. One of the parallel sides is thrice the other. Find the area (in sq.cm.) of the trapezium, if its perimeter is 8 cm. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='22' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABYAAAAQCAYAAAAS7Y8mAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKMSURBVDhPnZQ\/SFtRFMYf1qK0ihbiZKNJ\/LM1UHEQC7ZNOwm1rXaLSFxCav7MYpuKcUpiOrShauxSA7FQQ5YY6+IQKxkEMUM0i0pKDUYDYuKgMeHrvSdPW+QVbH7wePd899zvnXfveU9ACSSTSYyMjMDhcEheLpcLJRmHQiE4nU7kcrl\/XiUZj46OYmlpSYykKclYr9djZ2dHjKT5b+NMJoPBwUGcn5+LijSXxkdHR1heXkYstikq0qyvr8NisYjRn3XRaFRUipDxwkIQdXUyNDc342Z5OTvxNzQphc\/nw8TEBI2\/Ly5CJpOhqakJ1VXV0Gr7L99EOEilUFtTg7fWdyTMeDwQBAGxTenKbTYbFplhPp9H1e1beP7iJQqFAqIbG7Rubu4r5QnTU5NQKJUUpNNpZLNZrKys4Pj4mLSrGAwGbG9vo8CMg8EgDg8PST87OyNjz8xnigWL2Yz29nb09fZCLpejvr4e3+bnafIqJycn0Ol0OD09FZUiVquVrb2Lh48eiwozNhqN9KShISN2d3cxPm6jeGsrjnA4jI6ODvj9fkrmB2QymWh8QZZ1iW1sDAMDA8y8gZ1XiHTBzBIViuJWXFBZUYEPH92Ynf0CtVoNlUpFOn+A3W6nsRRPn2hwj+VzhKnJT6itvcP2KEcC50ZZGaY9MzTmVfI34He3241AIEB6mu2tRqPBj9VVijn9Wi1UrEM4Qmp\/n1XciGc9PVhbW8PQawMqKiuRSCQogcOr7u7uxvDwMOLxOGn8sFQqJRoaGhGJROD1eqkAh8NJ89THP5nJg85OKFl33G9rQ5h1xd\/wKvmirq4uaq0L9vZ+4VVfHytMgZaWFvZXey\/OiMbXobW1lT7l6wH8BhghlTQlDhGDAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='22' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABYAAAAQCAYAAAAS7Y8mAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJ5SURBVDhPnZRdSFphGMdPu2qzvPJytTyRd1Mvvcltrm662UaDVoboTXgRsY9AF4jknVq7mWOfNDfBWiO6KZ2NDNpC9EKyIXRT0FhSOYharjL1v\/M+HWNtJ9j8wcH3+T\/P8z\/veT\/kUAGZTAYDAwPweDySz\/DwMCoyDoVC8Hq9yOfzZz4VGTudTkQiETGSpiLjnp4erK6uipE0\/228u7sLi8WCo6MjUZHmxDidTiMajWJjc1NUpEkmk+jr6xMjYHt7m\/pSqZSoHEPGD+02yGQyNDY2Qi6XY3z8PSWlCAaDGBoaovGHcBgKhYL6amtqYTR2n3wJFxZ2mOM4RGY+olQq4f69u6iuPo9cLkcFf+JyuRAWDAuFAmpkF3Dj5i0Ui0WkFhfJZ3R0jOq4r2trmJ2NUsB4\/uwpFezs7IjKaaxWK1ZWVlAUjKemppDNZkk\/PDykvhcvX1F8ssZflpZg7Oqi5MjIa1E9zd7eHsxmMw4ODkTlGIfDgbq6i7hy9Zqo\/Ga8sLAAm80GrVaLltZW\/Nzfx9zcHHQ6HSYmJqiGbVBvby+Ny\/wQTolrcBAmk0kwr8f0dIj0v47b1tYmzdr\/5i38fj\/UajV4nqcce4Hb7aaxFC3XDbgs1DO4d2Nj6OzsoqDMuaoqPPY9oTGbJXsR+\/X5fJicnCT9u7C2BoMBn4UvLdNtNIIXTgiD+zQ\/T40P+vuRSCRwp6NDOBXVp24Wm3VbWxvsdjuWl5dJY5vF80rU119CLBZDIBAgH4\/HS3laihnh3ms0GiiVSjQ36xGPxylZhs2SNen1ejpaZdbXv+F2ezsaGhrQ1NQk\/Ks9EjMSa3wWKpWKrvK\/AfwCYuijLBeXDWoAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='22' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABYAAAAPCAYAAADgbT9oAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAI8SURBVDhPnZNfaFJhGMYlnVftotkWMxa4hGU6YeGVG8GCdtbdbhdUF9oQvBAF7Y+nyNT0Rky37q1E2LxRHOtevDQw7Sr\/NG+EeSkTcSpP5\/v8ktZxQf7gcN7n+c55znfe8x4JJuD09BQejwfhcHjsEYlEMFFwoVAAz\/MYDAYXHhMFR6NRxONxpsYzUbDD4UA+n2dqPP8d3Ov1YDKZ0Gq1mDMeUXAqlRJ285UpMdVqFRaLhSng8DADs9kMp9OJSqXC3L+CvxwdQSKR4KWbZ46YTCYDr9dLa97tptfb7XZw3AZmZmZQLpfp2ij4+PinsHAFcrkcfv875ooJhUJIJpO0frC5KYzXe1oT5FNTeON5S+tRsFZ7Gy7XM+iXl\/+5Y5vNhlKpxNSQer2Ovd1dKJXXhVH8Rj0a\/PoVj7W1u9S4ubg4emq\/38f+\/j7S6TTVnU6Hfjhy\/s1Zt4uH29tQKBRYWbmDZrNJfcnnTx8hvSTFwUESuVwOc7OzePT4CX4IvUokEtDpdJDJZGi326jVarBarfTGPyEbIFOi02lxf4OjnsTn88JoNGJ1dRUGg4H2eH5eCa\/Pj66wG\/L7SqVSxGIxZLNZBAIBeiNZCwaDQlu+U01wCZMxN3eN1qJxuyq8kuv5C6aGkHHSaDQ0iEwFod\/v4cbCApaWbqHRaKBYLGJ6+rLQKjNdFwVzHIfdvQ9MDSGzS8ZKrVbj5OSEuUBN8O+tr1NfpVLh6c7OqP+i4IvY2tqCXq9n6jzkbzwP8AuLXF2wgaAiHgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='22' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABYAAAAQCAYAAAAS7Y8mAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJdSURBVDhPnZQ\/TFpBHMdfrA2BsDBJNaEOgsw1JJDYgURW4mAniyQ42hGMhcQuDEQBQyyQECu1g7QKXbCmDkLAxphq\/6RuCgzUGEKIdaAxEvDbdz9Pay200U9yeff93t33vbvfe0\/ALSgUCnA6nZiammrafD4fbhUci8UQDAZRq9VatlsF2+12bG5uctWcGwefnZ3BZrOhXC5zpzk3Dj48PMTo6ChXrbkMzuX2kUqlxGuOO81Jp9MYHx\/nCqhUKrTu2+4ud86hYJdYYZlMBrVaDYlEgrGxJzTYjFAohHA4TP1EPA6FQoGenh7I5XJYrVbU63UaE+LLyxAEASsr78h48zpGen09Rfo6DoeDCndycoI7bW14bBmhc9\/e\/kjrluMJmid82tnB7OxzEhfcbW+H1+fn6k8uCnd6eopkMonj42Pyf1arFByNviT9V\/G83mmakM\/nufObUqlEwewJL2D9pxMT6Oy8hwGTibvXgl8tLFDo3NwL0ktLS9DpdMhms6QzmQwdxVV+HB3h2eQkhoeHoVLdx\/u1NfIvg6fFT5GFhnhhquLWPB6POFkFvV5PXiQSoeK14mF\/Px709VGfgsPhEKRSKTY2PpB5ldXVVbphsViE2+2m141xcPAdRqMRn798Jc14NDQETa+W+kJscZEWWkasVAz2H1gUvb29fZrQaDTQ1dUFi8VC7y\/7QBhsR8qODvRqtdja2kJ0fp5yfP4ZGhdmZvwwiYfOmsFgoG2zlki8pQkM9sNhiwYHB7lzTqGQh9lsRnd3NzSaXgQCAT5yrXj\/QqlUwuVycfU\/gF+F0KIL+lkrYQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the number of equilateral triangles that can be formed by joining the vertices of a <i>n<\/i>-sided regular polygon is 9, then find the value of <i>n<\/i>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"27","CORRECT_ANSWER":"27","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If M and N are the roots of the quadratic equation <i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> - (<i>p<\/i> - 3)<i>x<\/i> - 2<i>p<\/i> - 1 = 0, where <i>p<\/i> is some real number, find the minimum value of M<sup>2<\/sup><sup> <\/sup>+ N<sup>2<\/sup>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"10","CORRECT_ANSWER":"10","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the lines 6<i>x<\/i> + 5<i>y<\/i> = 17 and <i>p<\/i><i>y<\/i> = <i>x<\/i> +1 intersect at one point, then how many integer values of p are possible such that the point of intersection has integer co-ordinates?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Mr. Kumar has two sons Ramesh and Suresh. The sum of seven times Ramesh\u2019s age and thirteen times Suresh\u2019s age is equal to Mr. Kumar\u2019s age, while the sum of twelve times Ramesh\u2019s age and eight times Suresh\u2019s age is equal to Mrs. Kumar\u2019s age. If the difference between Mr. Kumar\u2019s age and Mrs. Kumar\u2019s age is five years, find the difference between Ramesh\u2019s age and Suresh\u2019s age.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 year\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 years\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 years\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are two taps, P and Q, connected to a tank. P alone takes 16 hours more than the time taken by P and Q together to fill the tank, while Q alone takes 36 hours more than the time taken by P and Q together to fill the tank. How many hours will Q alone take to fill the tank? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"60","CORRECT_ANSWER":"60","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the sum of the squares of the first N natural numbers exceeds the sum of the first N natural numbers by 1600%, find the value of N.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"25","CORRECT_ANSWER":"25","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>P started a business with Rs.4,00,000. After three months, Q joined him with Rs.6,00,000. After six more months, R joined them with Rs.<i>x<\/i>. If at the end of the year, Q received Rs.24,000 as his share of the profit, out of a total annual profit of Rs.64000, find the value of <i>x<\/i>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"1400000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1400000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the sixth term of a geometric progression whose second term is 8 and common ratio, 4.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2048","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2048","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the average of N consecutive numbers is three times the smallest number of these consecutive numbers and the difference between the second largest number and the smallest number is 59, find the sum of these numbers. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2745","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2745","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The price of an article is marked up by 57.14% over its cost price. What should be the discount percentage offered so that the profit made on selling the product is 10%?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>28%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>30%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>39%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhngErAPcAAP\/\/\/\/\/bkDoAAAAAAAAAOpDb\/9uQOgA6kNv\/\/zpmttuQZv+2ZjpmZjo6kJCQkGa2\/2aQ2zqQ2zoAOmZYAP\/\/tmYAZrb\/\/wAAZv\/\/25A6Zra2kLZmAJA6ADqQtpBmkABmtrZmOmZmZmYAOrb\/27a225A6OtvbkDoAZmYAAABmkJDb25CQtpC2\/wA6Otu2trZmZpCQOjqQkLbbkABmZmY6kGa227b\/tjo6ANu2Zv\/b2wAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAngErAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRo0iTKl3KtKnTp1AnBhAwgEABiwYOIIjKtatXmwESAFBwleICBg22fl3Ltq3JBQO0UgwboIEDtW7z6t37EO6ABwEgADAQgSFhggEkTBjAWC7fx5AhU6hgQeDUARcqLzwsEEMGDVc3\/I1MujTby6MRYuDQGC9nAAs6eMBrurZtqAY+KFxdeIFu1IytgghR9rbx40k3PFBYd6tygpx5I59OXSgFEcUPLtC64MIIEgM5T\/\/W7DFxWdGOB8K1OvJ69oSX2XOcWvhh\/PcJ\/cq36N4g\/YUYlICfQ\/oNiJB5CqFnwgnkIdTfQQEw2FGEDV6EHm0FbYdhQRSgMEAKHOz32oXlSXAVggY91x4K+yXU4XLdVcifCCqs8NCLsGXGEIU5yhjRgwNdV+NC40klYYwObdBiQSg2BCQA\/fE4n4QZNYnQBrrthKCUBAVo4EYGDMCAiQxpCCV2G2EZAAt9yfUkQ29K9KaabDKX1kVxatcCmQdS6SSaQaLJpUaDWlRolxzoqKWJqC03UKOdceBoQWFWlZ1fjMWFoQsIWLnapAblGV5w2X1KkHsvNIhpawc9aSpCBij\/ql6mhUUIA2P1ASDaADEAKhCq5L2qnm6r7beqprDKKmyQFcjAp39U\/UWhrbgKtGuvxXVoKbWprYZZhRvU1x+mtTLII4\/eyjqQt5pCetSWfg7bUFZbmRmRlQxtkJ5B9MK2r0HdySDYRPpueKAAS+IY439IYmltiwEPrBBhq2V5L8JfQhcBvohJOK0AvWXmsK4tRglyj7rqlluGcmmocGbTeiyhwysjSiwHv8VbFLwyvkbgvw1xnJABS+YHNEEbzECDwYYVvZm6HVvA84NWJr10vjVwkOtEsfqIWFpCWyaz1GRGaAOgVkZZNoNRxuulrlsDELPUY7fdoJRzE5Tp3nz3\/+3334ADLhHPKYKa0K6MWQwb30eHza\/TSO+tuEGrQb343v8SnbGDvkbKGMxjowhk5V53WcINIUx+eaZHn7n5c46fa67Mzpb1pN1ys+0hqZRG8CC7oNNdGYXa8v4ole4dOhThp3aOkJnL2vfsxJCrJ1f0HKIQt0OaT\/TkVMvlTTygQHa4PYQmelY6nM5nz7fqYg8\/u\/xn29457uN\/WRcOWYKfu\/Cys4Co8Da\/pDDvUXdaiJm6N7jpHciB2pELA1WDMwCkSnqby5CO+qUeHSmpAAHUlVw+uK4KXtBoW\/FZQ5DEwR1B8HjyE97\/Ckay7OBvZrpBkulu4KiGWYV4KFhO16lShrISZslhyhPKAQXim4Jgb1cpEJBUphc9xDHmAU9kTBRLJSmC+MVwC7FiaiIFxkpBjV1Z+0AIdcUYbHnxiogCFWeaExEzNgh7liFT9AIYwmt1zluAGRuUPOS0IQIAjTjjUaViQJlBWopyrEFWEmf1SO0Yzz5UaREevbIAMFYnJp38ZBNVBDDdkNIhYRlLBtdywk\/SpJW1ISFiJMZEOMqNloM5X4aQJbcXq7ryl8DEUyOtZwKJFYmJByimxhYSmFwe8jOrDKY0p3mgBAASNfWBFDaXiajWXEZHsZkNNcdJTsNE4G2wgp9losU76TTRIMOJZjnn+UvRVE9Xnuzd15wDRunQ85\/zFJLWcmAwUXETmQjoznc4NEyAOnSazYHL0ew1sa1pC0RFI9FDN+rQkXH0oyDFCOlCStKSmvSkKE2pSlfK0pa69KUwjalMZ0rTmtr0pggJCAA7\" style=\"width: 414px; height: 43px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhHgAjAPcAAP\/\/\/\/+2ZgAAZrb\/\/\/\/\/tmYAAP\/\/25A6ADqQ2wA6OjoAZtuQZmZmOv\/bkJA6OpDb\/9uQOjoAAAAAAGa2\/2ZmtraQkNv\/\/zo6kABmtgA6kLZmAAAAOgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAHgAjAAAItgABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhwYDCBgwkECBiQINHEDQ0GICBRQBSAwpcAEDjg4bgARgwMEDggEQQEDZUCXFBhEk6JxAgAKAmRUs1FzZ4ILQABgg6NSZQShDmwCgQsAwcKZDDUs5KpWAEYDFDS8hih1LtqzZskvTql0r4azbt3DjyiWrkeZIsyY5elxJNqZVgVDH9vyJIGhUvmK3MhUauOzfwyQFFwALAKtOmnMza97MubNnAAEBADs=\" style=\"width: 30px; height: 35px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhHAAkAPcAAP\/\/\/\/+2ZgAAZrb\/\/wAAAAA6kNv\/\/\/\/\/tmYAAAA6OjoAZv\/bkDo6kGa2\/\/\/\/25A6ZtuQOjqQ27ZmADoAAJA6ANuQZmZmOmaQ27ZmOpDb\/zpmtmZmtraQkAAAOgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAHAAkAAAItgABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjShQYQMAAigQIFDAAIEDGjQoPIEig4OICBgZENjiZEkEDhgtKEnTw4KJAmjYVxswJAMLLgT4b7gQagSCEokJl9iwa4OXRjj8TSshIIMKCCVRXYs0YdaLXr2DDOqRKtqxZAmLTql3LVqwDCkVFUkUKsYKFogsuCMSQIWKACE8HLtAQ8cCGpRw4AuAbEQJZkIO\/Bl7cd6LIDn1Ztt3MubPntAEBADs=\" style=\"width: 28px; height: 36px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhFgAkAPcAAP\/\/\/9uQOgAAAAAAOpDb\/\/\/\/tmYAAAA6kNv\/\/\/\/bkDoAZrb\/\/7ZmAABmtmY6kGYAOjqQ2zpmtjoAAGa2\/zo6kP\/\/25A6AAAAZtuQZmZmOpA6Ov+2ZmZmtraQkNvbkAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAFgAkAAAIqgABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxADCBAwgEABAxMPIFCYQMECAAwaFHCAoMADAhw9AggAYWCCCAwTSBDQQOBFAS1TfgxQ06aBCTpXNkhAAUEFC0AVMph44eNSmhCjSp1KNeHEq1ivVt3KtavXg0dzyoTKEEOGlhU0EDiaNOEGCCwBdHSaE2EBDishdPBQVKhCiVcPeFAZl2HcixPYMrxYEcCGiT2\/Sp5MeXJAADs=\" style=\"width: 22px; height: 36px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Cannot be determined <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type your answer in the text box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If 3<em><sup>x<\/sup><\/em><sup> <\/sup><sup>+<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>3<\/sup> + 9<em><sup>x<\/sup><\/em><sup> <\/sup><sup>+<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>1<\/sup> = 7290, then what is the value of <i>x<\/i>? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"3","CORRECT_ANSWER":"3","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"}}